[HU translation of]:  sgniht eslaf fo dnik eviecrep ot elpoep fo tol a del evah hcihw ,aidem eht hguorht
[HU translation of]:  .nioctiB ni devlovni gnitteg yllaitnetop tuoba lacitpeks elpoep ekam ro siht tuoba
[HU translation of]:  .tah citpeks nioctiB ym no tup ot gniog m'I ,yakO
[HU translation of]:  ,ereht tuo shtym eht lla dna snrecnoc tseggib s'elpoep fo emos hguorht og s'teL
[HU translation of]:  ...htiw gnitrats
[HU translation of]:  suomynoduesp a si nioctiB fo rotnevni ehT
[HU translation of]:  .otomakaN ihsotaS fo eman eht yb laudividni
[HU translation of]:  .era yeht ebyam ro ehs ro eh ohw swonk eno on tuB
[HU translation of]:  .eman sih yb nwonk gnieb reven fo noisiced tnaillirb eht edam ihsotaS oS
[HU translation of]:  .mynoduesp a si ihsotaS
[HU translation of]:  .eman ekaf a s'tI
[HU translation of]:  dna yenom enimrednu yllatnemadnuf uoy fi dootsrednu ihsotaS kniht I os dnA
[HU translation of]:  .taht tuoba yppah yrev eb ot gniog ton er'yeht ,yenom revo lortnoc s'tnemnrevog
[HU translation of]:  erehw tniop kaew a emoceb era uoy ,nioctiB fo egami ro ecaf cilbup eht era uoy fi oS
[HU translation of]:  ni yllaudividni uoy kcatta dluoc stnemnrevog
[HU translation of]:  .nioctiB enilrednu thgim taht taht sepoh eht
[HU translation of]:  .ytilibisiv fo tros taht morf flesmih devomer ihsotaS os dnA
[HU translation of]:  susrev ti revo noitpecrep ruo segnahc ti ,yenom eht ot ecaf a tup ew fI
[HU translation of]:  s'ohw enoyna evah t'ndluohs yenom a erehw gniht lacitilop a ,lartuen siht gnieb ti
[HU translation of]:  s'nioctiB ,wonk uoy ,ti dniheb redael lartnec a
[HU translation of]:  .dezilartneced s'ti taht si esoprup eritne lluf
[HU translation of]:  tub ,suomynona tius ylno ton lliw ihsotaS os dnA
[HU translation of]:  .tcejorp eht morf flesmih devomer yllautneve eh neht
[HU translation of]:  gnimoceb nioctiB ni pets tnatropmi na saw taht kniht I dnA
[HU translation of]:  .srotcev kcatta lacitilop gnivomer dna dezilartneced
[HU translation of]:  .redael lartnec a evah muerehtE ,wonk uoy ,ekil stessa rehto saerehW
[HU translation of]:  uoy ,ro detserra steg kilatiV fi sneppah tahw tuB
[HU translation of]:  .mih ot sneppah dab gnihtemos dibrof gnivah ,wonk
[HU translation of]:  .metsysoce muerehtE eht ta dna tniop kaew a s'eH
[HU translation of]:  yllatnemadnuf yrev dootsrednu ,kniht I ,ihsotaS
[HU translation of]:  .tuoba s'ti dna tuoba saw nioctiB tahw
[HU translation of]:  dna yenom revo lortnoc s'etats eht gnignellahc
[HU translation of]:  .yenom nwo rieht evah ot modeerf eht elpoep gnivig
[HU translation of]:  .kcab ruoy no tegrat a evah ot gniog er'uoy ,taht ekil gnihtemos od uoy nehw dnA
[HU translation of]:  .yenom lartuen s'ti os ,yakO
[HU translation of]:  .eurt eb ot doog oot sdnuoS
[HU translation of]:  ?nioctiB nab dlrow eht dnuora stnemnrevog t'noW
[HU translation of]:  .elbaknihtnu ylriaf si nioctiB nab ot tnemnrevog SU eht roF
[HU translation of]:  .deveihca eb yllacitcarp yllautca dluow taht woh wonk t'nod I
[HU translation of]:  .dezilartneced si ytidommoc a eb ot degdelwonkca si ti taht neviG
[HU translation of]:  .taht od ot snoitnetni yllautca era ereht taht kniht t'nod I
[HU translation of]:  esoht ot nepo yllautca era ohw srotaluger ynam era erehT
[HU translation of]:  .esiwrehto dna llih eht no srekamycilop sa llew sa stifeneb
[HU translation of]:  .sediced tnemnrevog SU eht tahw si yllaer taerht tseggib ehT
[HU translation of]:  nioctiB gnitaert si tnemnrevog SU eht ,wonk ew sa tuB
[HU translation of]:  .elbaiv s'ti gnihtemos sa ti ta skool ti taht yaw a ni
[HU translation of]:  .nioctiB ruoy barg ot seirt ,taht seod tnemnrevog eno fI
[HU translation of]:  .lagelli ti ekam ro yawa ti ekat ro tniop
[HU translation of]:  .ereh lagel s'nioctiB ,llew ,yas dna pu pop lliw tnemnrevog rehtonA
[HU translation of]:  .lirep nwo rieht ta ti od ,elpoep morf ti ekat ot yrt ohw stnemnrevog eseht oS
[HU translation of]:  .noitpyrcne edarg yratilim ni depparw yenom latigid detubirtsid si nioctiB oS
[HU translation of]:  .ytilibavivrus rof dezimitpO
[HU translation of]:  .kcatta level etats noitan a dnatshtiw ot dengised s'ti oS
[HU translation of]:  osla s'ti tub ,taerht tsetaerg eht si taht oS
[HU translation of]:  .rof tliub esoprup sah nioctiB taerht eht
[HU translation of]:  fo tnemtrapeD eht susrev nietsnreB sa nwonk esac truoc tnatropmi na s'erehT
[HU translation of]:  hsilbup ot detnaw rosseforp ytisrevinu a erehw ,ecitsuJ
[HU translation of]:  .detaerc eh taht erawtfos noitpyrcne ro erawtfos yhpargotpyrc
[HU translation of]:  eb erawtfos taht taht eriuqer snoitaluger laredef hguorht tnemnrevog eht woN
[HU translation of]:  thguoht nietsnreB dna meht ot dettimbus
[HU translation of]:  .sthgir tnemdnema tsrif sih tsniaga saw siht
[HU translation of]:  gninniw yletamitlu pu dedne dna tnemnrevog eht tsniaga tiuswal a delif yllautca eh oS
[HU translation of]:  si egaugnal ro gnimmargorp erawtfos taht dediced saw ti erehw tiuswal taht
[HU translation of]:  .noitutitsnoC eht fo tnemdnemA tsriF eht rednu hceeps sa detcetorp
[HU translation of]:  .erawtfos yhpargotpyrc si nioctiB esuaceb nioctiB htiw tnatropmi si sihT
[HU translation of]:  detcetorp osla s'ti taht kniht dluow uoy oS
[HU translation of]:  .noitutitsnoC eht fo tnemdnemA tsriF eht rednu
[HU translation of]:  .nrecnoc gib a si ereht tub ,ti nab thgirtuo t'now yeht ebyam oS
[HU translation of]:  .nwod tuhs eb wohemos nac nioctiB
[HU translation of]:  .yaw euqinu yrev a ni detcurtsnoc s'ti esuaceb ylniam deyortsed eb tonnac nioctiB
[HU translation of]:  eht dah taht dlrow eht ni retupmoc elgnis yreve yortsed ot elba erew uoy sselnu
[HU translation of]:  .deyortsed eb t'nac ti ,retupmoc rieht no nioctiB fo edoc
[HU translation of]:  eht gninnur saw taht enihcam elgnis yreve nwod tuhs dna og ot elba erew uoy sselnU
[HU translation of]:  ,krowten eht gniruces yllautca saw dna erawtfos gninim
[HU translation of]:  .flesti krowten eht yortsed ro nwod tuhs t'nac uoy
[HU translation of]:  yreve morf syek etavirp eht evomer dna og ot elba er'uoy sselnu yletamitlu neht dnA
[HU translation of]:  t'nac uoy ,ti sdloh taht dlrow eht ni nosrep elgnis
[HU translation of]:  .rehtie sevlesmeht snioctib laudividni eht yortsed
[HU translation of]:  dna metsys reep-ot-reep dezilartneced siht ,erawtfos ecruos nepo siht nevig os dnA
[HU translation of]:  a dehcaer sah won ti ,flah a dna edaced a revo detcurtsnoc neeb s'ti taht tcaf eht
[HU translation of]:  ?nwod dewols eb ti dluoc ,truh eb ti dluoc erehw level
[HU translation of]:  .eruS
[HU translation of]:  deen tsuj uoy si deen uoy lla yletamitlu esuaceb deyortsed eb tonnac ti tuB
[HU translation of]:  .nioctiB evah uoy dna gninnur dlrow eht ni erehwemos retupmoc eno no eb ot edoc eht
[HU translation of]:  gniniur si nioctiB kniht elpoep fo tol a tub ,yakO
[HU translation of]:  .ygrene hcum oot yaw sesu ti esuaceb tnemnorivne eht
[HU translation of]:  .taht erolpxe s'tel oS
[HU translation of]:  nioctiB eht gnitarepo selbawener fo egatnecrep ehT
[HU translation of]:  .hgih ylgnikcohs yllautca si gninim rof krowten
[HU translation of]:  .ygrene neerg si gninim nioctiB rof desu s'taht rewop tsoM
[HU translation of]:  s'ti os dna ygrene etsaw s'ti ,ygrene elbawener s'tI
[HU translation of]:  .tenalp eht fo tnirptoof nobrac eht ot gnidda ton yllautca
[HU translation of]:  labolg eht fo flah revo pu sekam hcihw ,licnuoc gninim nioctiB eht ot gnidroccA
[HU translation of]:  nioctiB fo %85 yletamixorppa ,krowten gninim nioctiB
[HU translation of]:  .ygrene elbawener dna neerg ezilitu snoitarepo gninim
[HU translation of]:  elbawener tsehgih eht sah gninim nioctiB taht snaem sihT
[HU translation of]:  .dlrow eht ni yrtsudni rehto yna fo puekam xim leuf
[HU translation of]:  taht si nioctiB tuoba gniht taerg eht dnA
[HU translation of]:  .elibom s'ti dna suoenatnatsni si gninim nioctiB
[HU translation of]:  ohw esoht era srenim nioctiB lufsseccus tsom eht tub ,ygrene eht esahc nac uoy oS
[HU translation of]:  eht si ygrene tsepaehc eht dna ygrene tsepaehc eht dnif
[HU translation of]:  .tnemnorivne eht ot egamad tsael eht seod taht ygrene
[HU translation of]:  .selbawener ot noitisnart eht gnidael si ,gninim krow fo foorp ,gninim nioctiB
[HU translation of]:  ,secruos ygrene neerg dna naelc ot noitisnart a tuoba erac ohw esoht rof oS
[HU translation of]:  gninim nioctiB gnicarbme eb dluohs yllaer yeht
[HU translation of]:  .ereht teg ot gniog era ew woh si siht esuaceb
[HU translation of]:  .seirtnuoc llams eseht sa ygrene hcum sa esu hcum os esu
[HU translation of]:  ?yrtsudni gniknab eht naht tnereffid naem uoy ,yakO
[HU translation of]:  ?krow ot emoh yaw ruoy ni yb evird uoy od ,sehcnarb naem I
[HU translation of]:  ?knab eht ni neeb ti saH
[HU translation of]:  detaeh gnieb sgnidliub gib eseht evah ew od yhW
[HU translation of]:  ?gnihton gniod dnuora gnittis elpoep dna delooc dna
[HU translation of]:  .rehto hcae ot yenom eriw ew ,sdrac MTA ruo esu lla eW
[HU translation of]:  .sgniht fo tol a ni desu s'taht yticirtcele fo tol a s'ereht oS
[HU translation of]:  .nioctiB sa yticirtcele fo tnuoma eht semit xis sesu gninim dloG
[HU translation of]:  .eulav ot redro otni ygrene ekat ot si ,yad yreve ,su fo lla ,od ew gnihtyreve
[HU translation of]:  .eulav ot ygrene fo noisrevnoc tcefrep eht eb yllautca nac nioctiB
[HU translation of]:  ,kcalb yllatot s'ti ,thgin ta setatS detinU eht fo erutcip eht nees reve uoY
[HU translation of]:  .saxeT tseW dna atokaD htroN rof tpecxe
[HU translation of]:  ?yhW
[HU translation of]:  ?thgir ,sag gniralf er'yeht esuaceB
[HU translation of]:  .tuo semoc taht sag emos s'ereht dna lio ecudorp yehT
[HU translation of]:  yllaretil yeht os ,senilepip yna evah t'nod yehT
[HU translation of]:  .erif no ti thgil yeht dna ria eht ni pu ti tup
[HU translation of]:  .wohs thgil looc ,wonk uoy ,tnemnorivne eht rof dab yllaeR
[HU translation of]:  .evitagen a s'taht tub
[HU translation of]:  ?od ew dluoc tahw oS
[HU translation of]:  orcim a hcatta dluoc ew dna ,sag taht ekat dluoc eW
[HU translation of]:  .ylkciuq otni yticirtcele nrut dluoc ew dna ,ti ot enibrut
[HU translation of]:  .ti ot renim a hcatta dluoc eW
[HU translation of]:  .eulav taht dnes ot enilepip a deen t'nod ew ,woN
[HU translation of]:  .noitcennoc tenretni na si deen ew llA
[HU translation of]:  ,sdrib yna llik ot deen t'nod uoy ,yawa thgir teg ot deen t'nod eW
[HU translation of]:  .smraf dniw dna sllimdniw
[HU translation of]:  .eulav ot ygrene fo noisrevnoc tcefrep a si taht dnA
[HU translation of]:  .su rof evitisop ten a yllautca s'tI
[HU translation of]:  .sag deralf eht morf tuo nobrac eht gnikat er'ew tnemnorivne eht
[HU translation of]:  .taht tuoba sklat eno on tub ,evitisop eguh a s'tahT
[HU translation of]:  t'nod ,sknab eht tnaw t'nod stnebmucni eht esuaceB
[HU translation of]:  .yenom fo mrof retteb a ot noitargim siht tnaw
[HU translation of]:  .erehwyna og nac yenom nioctiB ehT
[HU translation of]:  .tenalp eht no erehwyna og nac tI
[HU translation of]:  ew esuaceb erehwyna yllautriv si hcihw ,noitcennoc tenretni na s'erehT
[HU translation of]:  .snoitcennoc tenretni edivorp taht setilletas evah
[HU translation of]:  .llifdnal a fo pot no nwod polp nac ti dnA
[HU translation of]:  .mraf yriad a fo pot no nwod polp nac tI
[HU translation of]:  .retaw etsaw fo pot no nwod polp nac tI
[HU translation of]:  .ytilicaf tnemtaert
[HU translation of]:  nac ti dna enahtem taht ekat nac ti dnA
[HU translation of]:  .sag elbammalf a si enahtem esuaceb ti tsubmoc
[HU translation of]:  .2OC otni ti nrut dna enahtem taht htiw yticirtcele etareneg nac ti dnA
[HU translation of]:  no tcapmi evitisop yrev a gnivah er'uoy ,siht gniod er'uoy taht emityna dnA
[HU translation of]:  naht esrow semit 48 si sag esuohneerg a sa enahtem esuaceb tnemnorivne eht
[HU translation of]:  .doirep raey 001 revo esrow semit 72 dna doirep raey 02 revo edixoid nobrac
[HU translation of]:  fo gnihtemos detaerc yllautca ev'uoy won oS
[HU translation of]:  .tnemnorivne eht pu gninaelc er'uoy elihw eulav
[HU translation of]:  .erom emoceb ot gniog si gninim nioctiB ,noinipo ym ni dnA
[HU translation of]:  sloot lufrewop tsom eht fo eno si ydaerla noinipo ym dna
[HU translation of]:  .derevocsid reve ev'ew taht tnemnorivne eht pu gninaelc rof
[HU translation of]:  ?syug dab yb desu nioctiB t'nsi ,tiaw tuB
[HU translation of]:  fi od ot tnaw dluow uoy gniht tsal eht ,tuo gnidnif peek slanimirc emos sA
[HU translation of]:  swollof taht ereht tuo regdel cilbup a tup si yenom fo hcnub a laets ot gniyrt er'uoy
[HU translation of]:  .tixe na evah uoy litnu ekam uoy taht evom yreve
[HU translation of]:  gnineppah saw ytivitca suoirafen fo tol a ,nioctiB fo syad ylrae eht dnA
[HU translation of]:  .ygolonhcet wen siht tpoda ot kciuq erew yeht sa ereht
[HU translation of]:  .egnahcxe fo muidem a sa nioctiB esu t'nod yllaer uoy ,wonk uoy ,er'uoy fi ,won dnA
[HU translation of]:  ylnepo klat ot gnilliw era ohw ,yrtsudni ecnegilletni eht ni era ohw elpoep morF
[HU translation of]:  nac yeht esuaceb nioctiB esu slanimirc nehw referp yllautca yeht ,nioctiB tuoba
[HU translation of]:  .sdohtem laiceps emos gnisu nwod meht kcart yllautca
[HU translation of]:  .etavirp yllatot ton s'ti tub ,etavirp si tI
[HU translation of]:  fo egatnecrep eht taht si ytilaer eht ,revewoH
[HU translation of]:  .wol yrev ,yrev si otpyrc nihtiw emirc laicnanif
[HU translation of]:  .snosaer fo rebmun a rof s'taht dnA
[HU translation of]:  .ni tsevni ot reisae si tI
[HU translation of]:  ycnerrucotpyrc ni emirc laicnanif dna duarf teg ot
[HU translation of]:  .metsys laicnanif lanoitidart eht ni naht
[HU translation of]:  .sniahckcolb fo seitreporp evitan eht fo esuaceb yllaer s'taht dnA
[HU translation of]:  .elbaecart s'ti dna regdel eht no sraeppa noitcasnart yrevE
[HU translation of]:  .suomynona si nioctiB kniht elpoeP
[HU translation of]:  .ton s'tI
[HU translation of]:  .suomynona oduesp s'tI
[HU translation of]:  syug dab tuoba emit eht lla seirots raeh uoy dnA
[HU translation of]:  .ecnallievrus niahckcolb gnisu thguac gnitteg fo dnik
[HU translation of]:  .nwod elpoep kcart ot elbissop si tI
[HU translation of]:  ,egnahcxe xeniftiB eht ,egnahcxe na tsniaga kcah a saw ereht ,6102 nI
[HU translation of]:  .noillim 07$ erehw
[HU translation of]:  .nelots saw nioctiB fo srallod
[HU translation of]:  tpmetta srerednual eht ,sraey xis txen eht revo ,lleW
[HU translation of]:  .snoitcasnart etacsufbo ot sdnuf esoht evom ot
[HU translation of]:  dna stekram ten krad dna secivres gnixim ekil seuqinhcet noitacsufbo esu yehT
[HU translation of]:  .koob eht ni euqinhcet gnirednual yreve yllaer dna snioc decnahne ytimynona
[HU translation of]:  lanimirc SRI ,retal sraey xis ,retal sraey evif ,wonk uoy ,lleW
[HU translation of]:  esoht kcab ezies ot elba yllautca saw snoitagitsevni
[HU translation of]:  .ytiC kroY weN ni slaudividni owt tserra dna sdnuf
[HU translation of]:  ,retal sraey xis ro evif ,wonk uoy ,ecalp koot yllautca eruzies eht nehw dnA
[HU translation of]:  .4$ tuoba htrow won erew emit eht ta noillim 07$ erew taht sdnuf esoht
[HU translation of]:  .yrotsih SU ni gnihtyna fo eruzies tsegral eht ti gnikam ,noillib 2
[HU translation of]:  .yrots ycnerrucotpyrc ni ylno na si tahT
[HU translation of]:  .seicnerruc lanoitidart ni neppah ton seod esac tahT
[HU translation of]:  eht tsuj ton s'ti si yranidroartxe os s'tahW
[HU translation of]:  .snoitcasnart ycnerrucotpyrc ecart nac taht tnemnrevog
[HU translation of]:  .ydobyreve si tI
[HU translation of]:  .nelots gnieb nioctiB fo draeh evah elpoep emoS
[HU translation of]:  ?dekcah eb nac nioctiB naem taht seod oS
[HU translation of]:  .dekcah eb t'naC
[HU translation of]:  .dekcah eb tonnac nioctiB
[HU translation of]:  nwo sti ni stis yllaer nioctiB ,otpyrc ot wen fo tros s'ohw enoemos rof ,seY
[HU translation of]:  ,regdel eht gnitcetorp ,wonk uoy ,ytiruces si sucof yramirp sti esuaceb rotcev
[HU translation of]:  .seirtne tneluduarf etaerc ot yrt ot evisnepxe ti gnikam dna krow fo foorp gnisu
[HU translation of]:  .napaJ ni no desab egnahcxe t'nsaw ereht ,4102 ni kcaB
[HU translation of]:  .emit eht ta naidotsuc nioctiB tsegral eht saw tI
[HU translation of]:  .rekcah naissuR a yb dekcah saw egnahcxe siht ,4102 ni dnA
[HU translation of]:  na dna seitilibarenluv ytirucesrebyc evah nac segnahcxe taht eurt si ti oS
[HU translation of]:  .nioctiB laets ot taht etartlifni yllautca dluoc redurtni
[HU translation of]:  .dekcah eb tonnac ,erawtfos eht ,flesti nioctiB tuB
[HU translation of]:  .deppots eb t'nac yllautca tI
[HU translation of]:  eniaM fo renroc eht no knab a ekil tsomla sa nioctiB tuoba kniht uoy ,wonk uoY
[HU translation of]:  ekil neht dna won yreve ekil fo tros dna eniaM dna
[HU translation of]:  .knab eht bor ot ni emoc ot stnaw rebbor knab emos
[HU translation of]:  yad yreve fo dnoces elgnis yreve ti dnuora srebbor knab fo sdnasuoht sah nioctiB
[HU translation of]:  .egallip dna kcatta ot ytilibarenluv a rof gnikool
[HU translation of]:  dna ytiruces fo etar rehgih hcum a ta si ti os dnA
[HU translation of]:  .edaced a revo rof dnuora neeb s'ti taht won ecnedifnoc
[HU translation of]:  ?dekcah teg uoy t'nod tub ,llew ,yas elpoep dnA
[HU translation of]:  .emit eht lla dekcah gnitteg era sknab eht tuo snrut ,lleW
[HU translation of]:  .yad yrevE
[HU translation of]:  .dekcah saw I
[HU translation of]:  .sknab evom ot dah I
[HU translation of]:  .rebmun enohp ym egnahc ot dah I
[HU translation of]:  .gnihtyreve egnahc ot dah I
[HU translation of]:  .knab a hguorht saw taht tuB
[HU translation of]:  .niahckcolb nioctiB eht dekcah reve sah doow no kconk yadot eno oN
[HU translation of]:  .knab
[HU translation of]:  .rebmun enohp ym egnahc ot dah I